Preliminary Guide to the Joel Raphaelson Papers, 1950-2000
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Joel Raphaelson papers 1950-2000
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Raphaelson, Joel.
Extent: 1500 items 3.2 linear feet
Joel Raphaelson served as the Executive Creative Director of Ogilvy & Mather Worldwide. Collection includes speeches, presentations, correspondence, audiovisual materials, and printed material relating to Raphaelson's career with Ogilvy & Mather. Also includes some publications and presentations about effective business writing. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising, and Marketing History.
raphaelsonjoel
Language: Materials in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restricted.
Collection is closed.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
Gift, 2007 (2007-0191), 3.2 lin. ft.
Biographical / Historical Note
Joel Raphaelson served as the Executive Creative Director of Ogilvy & Mather Worldwide. He worked closely with David Ogilvy, and was a permanent member of the Ogilvy's Creative Council, an international group.
Collection Overview
Collection includes speeches, presentations, correspondence, audiovisual materials, and printed materials and publications relating to his career with Ogilvy & Mather. Also includes some publications and presentations about effective business writing. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising, and Marketing History.
Subject Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Advertising -- United States -- History; Ogilvy, David, 1911-1999; Raphaelson, Joel; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising, and Marketing History.; Ogilvy & Mather; Videotapes; Audiotapes; Publications; Color slides; Correspondence
Contents of Collection
- Joel Raphaelson Papers, 1950-2000, 4 Boxes
  This is a preliminary finding aid representing an unprocessed collection. Materials have been reboxed, but the original folders and order have been maintained. Folders are listed by the names given to them by the creator. Audiovisual materials have been filed in Box 4.
  - Joel-Europe Assignment (Box 1)
  - Ogilvy & Mather, Staff Meeting 1972 Dec. 18
  - The People Book: Ogilvy & Mather guidelines on how to attract the best people and lead them to do their best
  - The Benevolent Dictators: Interviews with Advertising Greats
  - How to be a good creative director
  - Jock Elliott, (3 folders)
  - Speeches, presentations, articles
  - Is the Bug Dead? The Great Beetle Ad Campaign
  - How to Write Better: The Ogilvy & Mather guide to writing effective memos, letters, reports, plans and strategies, by Ken Roman and Joel Raphaelson, (2 copies)
  - Old Time Agriculture in the Ads
  - There is Nothing New About Change
  - Speeches and Suits
  - The Creative Concept: a Mathers Paper
  - Who We Are, and Where We're Not Going
  - Principles of Account Management, by William E. Phillips
  - Ogilvy & Mather Annual Report, 1972
  - Ogilvy & Mather Annual Report, 1967
  - David Ogilvy's Creative Council missives
  - Flagbearer: Ogilvy & Mather Annual Staff Meeting, 1966
  - Some David Ogilvy speeches, saved by Joel Raphaelson, (2 folders)
  - Magic Lanterns: Weekly Reports
  - Magic Lanterns: David Ogilvy correspondence, (2 folders)
  - Flagbearer newsletters, 1979, 1988-1989
  - Correspondence with Jock Elliott
  - Miscellaneous correspondence and publications, 1960s-1980s
  - Ogilvy & Mather Chicago: a report on our first five years
  - Correspondence with David Ogilvy, (3 folders) (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1991-1996, (3 folders)
  - DOVE campaign poster drafts, 1950s (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous advertisements by others
  - Batten, Barton, Durstine, & Osborn, Inc. materials and drafts, 1953-1958
  - The Idea
  - Making Red Redder: Ogilvy & Mather Worldwide's credentials
  - Directory of Services and Sources, Ogilvy & Mather Worldwide
  - Framed advertisement and response for Rums of Puerto Rico
  - Radio Freak slides (Box 4)
  - Current Reel 1/82 Radio Freak (open reel magnetic audiotape)
  - Radio Freak Original Presentation (open reel audiotape 19 cm/s)
  - Ogilvy & Mather Magic Lanterns: David Ogilvy Intro, 1986, dubbed 1997 (VHS)
  - Ogilvy & Mather Direct: David Ogilvy Presentation, 1988, dubbed 1997 (VHS)
  - Ogilvy & Mather Classics (3/4 inch Umatic videotape)